<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><?xml-stylesheet href="/feed_style.xsl" type="text/xsl"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="https://www.rssboard.org/media-rss">
  <channel>
    <title>Reccomendations on Dom Goodwin</title>
    <link>http://192.168.0.30:1313/categories/reccomendations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reccomendations on Dom Goodwin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Dom Goodwin</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 15:06:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://192.168.0.30:1313/categories/reccomendations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><icon>http://192.168.0.30:1313/logo.svg</icon>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The case for time-tracking</title>
      <link>http://192.168.0.30:1313/posts/case-for-timetracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 15:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.0.30:1313/posts/case-for-timetracking/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Time tracking has a bad reputation, it invokes images of managers watching over your shoulder or pay being docked as you punched in minutes before your shift ended. Due to these, and many more, if you suggest to someone to start tracking their time they’re likely to look at you like you’ve gone mad.</p>
<p>I think time tracking, for your own benefit, can be a great way to be introspective about how you work and allow you a greater understanding of managing distractions, context switching and when you’re feeling productive.</p>
<h2 id="what-is-time-tracking">What is time tracking</h2>
<p>The basic gist is, you start a timer when you are working on something. Whilst you could track time per ticket or some other fine grained metric, I would strongly recommend tracking categories of activities.</p>
<p>Ones I track are:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Development</strong> - directly coding, usually “when I’m in my IDE”</li>
<li><strong>Live support</strong> - picking up alerts that have fired or investigating issues/incidents</li>
<li><strong>Messaging</strong> - slack messaging people</li>
<li><strong>Meetings</strong> - time spent in any meetings
<ul>
<li>I found it in the past useful to <em>tag</em> these “ceremonies”, “1-1s”, “other”</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Break</strong> - Going to grab a coffee or lunch
<ul>
<li>This one could be tracked by just not running a timer, but I find ending the Break timer when I return is a useful trigger to start working</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Collaboration</strong> - Working with someone else to either plan, pair or debug</li>
</ul>
<p>These activities can also be expanded with tags if you want to know more detail, things like whether the activity is for client a or b can be useful if that fits your environment.</p>
<p>I’ve also found adding activities when you want to focus on a particular area, say “Documentation” or “Reading tech books” can help you focus energy towards a goal.</p>
<p>A key thing with the tracking is not being too detailed, it’s not useful to know ticket-12 took twice as long as ticket-14 in the scheme of things (even if Toggl do like to push jira integration). You’re not billing people for this time, it’s just about gaining understanding.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-time-track">How to time track</h2>
<p>This might seem like an obvious area “set timer to start when you work on something” but there’s some nuance and tips I can share.</p>
<ul>
<li>If at any point you stop working on your current task for distractions, stop said timer (and set a new one if applicable)
<ul>
<li>A common thing might be you need to respond to someones message, ideally you try to batch these where possible and the people messaging you <a href="https://www.nohello.com/">don’t just say hi</a>, so maybe after 30minutes, stop the timer, start the messaging timer and respond to people</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Before you begin any activity, start the timer
<ul>
<li>I find this is a useful way of getting in the mindset for that task too, it forces you to mentally think “what am I working on right now” instead of just falling into work</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>You can always update past timers if you forget too, don’t try to be too accurate, to the nearest 5 minutes should show you the gist of it.</li>
<li>“Doesn’t this add to the context switching load?” <strong>Yes</strong> I believe it does, but that isn’t a problem. It should be harder for you to switch what task you’re working on to avoid (where possible) context switching and having to recognize you’re doing it, stop and start a timer, adds to the overhead, it’s way too easy to down tools on work to respond to slack.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="what-time-tracking-is-not">What time tracking is not</h2>
<p>It’s important to call out what personal time tracking is not, and avoid some of the pitfalls.</p>
<ul>
<li>Time tracking should be for your own benefit, and you should be the only one who sees the data. You’re not doing this to prove to your manager at year-end reviews you keep working even when you sneeze or to compare to your team. On the other side, this shouldn’t be something a manager imposes on you and wants to see progress reports.</li>
<li>Related to above, it’s important to be honest when time tracking. Everyone has bad days for productivity and just leaving “development” timer on won’t help you understand anything. This timer is just meant to be data on how you work, no opinions or judgement.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="benefits-of-time-tracking">Benefits of time tracking</h2>
<p>I’ve personally found tracking my time, even for short 1 month stints, a great way to introspect on your working habits.</p>
<p>A good example is at the end of the day, when you might be feeling like it was (or wasn’t) a productive day. Being able to look back and go “oh, those 4 meetings 30minutes apart basically translated to 4hrs of meetings for my productivity”. I’ve commonly found days when I’m feeling unproductive, I can look at my time tracked for the day and understand why.</p>
<p>Another key aspect is seeing the effect interrupts have on you, everyone knows the bane of context switching at this point, but being able to see the switch in activity and then the lull between starting anew is clear.</p>
<p>I’ve also found having to think about <em>starting</em> a task, having a timer to start when I go into development mode helps mentally adjust to the task at hand.</p>
<h2 id="tools-and-use-and-how-to-set-them-up">Tools and use and how to set them up</h2>
<p>For actually tracking the time, I use: <a href="https://toggl.com/track/">toggl track</a>. Honestly, I don’t particularly like it but I haven’t found an alternative that does everything I need and don&rsquo;t need to install.</p>
<p>I’ve previous used <a href="https://timeryapp.com/">Timery</a>, which makes it easier to change timer and highly recommend it to never interact with toggl. I would highly recommend this when you can install applications on your own machine and for iOS if you have it.</p>
<ul>
<li>I have a pinned tab open in my browser with toggl, it goes grey when there isn’t one active which I find useful
<ul>
<li>Timery will sit in the top bar of my Mac which makes using it easier</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>I then setup a widget on my phone home screen. This helps me spot any timers I’ve left running.</li>
</ul>
<p>Within toggl, I have the activities I listed above as “Projects”. I don’t use any tags currently but I’ve found it useful in the past when working across teams or clients.</p>
<ul>
<li>A good rule is a project should be something important to you but broad enough you don’t need to think or decide which one to use when starting a timer. It should be obvious what the work you’re doing is.</li>
<li>As an example for tags, I wanted to see which client’s live issues were taking the most time in my day.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="to-round-up">To round up</h2>
<p>Time tracking can be a useful tool to gain insight into your working habits and productivity. I’d recommend only doing it when you’re gaining something from it; in the past I’ve used it for 1-3month stints when feeling unproductive or joining a new company. If you’re doing it and finding the data not useful.</p>]]></description>
      
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts reccomendations - 07/2019</title>
      <link>http://192.168.0.30:1313/posts/podcasts-2019-q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 11:28:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.0.30:1313/posts/podcasts-2019-q2/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>These are my currently podcast reccomendations for Q2 2019</p>
<h2 id="the-teachers-pet">The Teacher&rsquo;s Pet</h2>
<p>A great true crime podcast exploring a 36 year old cold case around a woman who went missing and who&rsquo;s husband brought his 17 year old, school girl, girlfriend into the house within 2 days.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Ep. 1: Bayview</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-weeds">The Weeds</h2>
<p>Podcast from Vox where they do a deep dive into a topic for ~1hr. If you pick an episode with an good topic usually very informative and interesting listen.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started-1">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Americas two housing crises</li>
<li>Into the weeds with Elizabeth Warren</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="gangster-capitalism">Gangster Capitalism</h2>
<p>Series 1 of the podcast covers the admissions scandal with some truly horrific stories of entitled parents. The podcast really going into the inner works of the scams being done and the unprecedented scale of the system in place.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started-2">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>S1 [1] The Side Door</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-shrink-next-door">The Shrink Next Door</h2>
<p>A deeply interesting and weird story around a therapist who abused his position with his patients. Focuses mainly on this one individual who got taken advantage of to a ridiculous level, leading to him being ostracised from his family and friends.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started-3">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Welcome To The Neighborhood | 1</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="dissect">Dissect</h2>
<p>Season 4 of Dissect covers Tyler the Creators album, Flower Boy. An amazing and indepth look into this brilliant album with some bonus episodes covering some of his over work including his new album, Igor.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started-4">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>S4E1 - Tyler the Creator: Flower Boy</li>
<li>Dissecting Igor with Anthony Fantano</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>]]></description>
      
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast reccomendations - 02/2019</title>
      <link>http://192.168.0.30:1313/posts/podcasts-2019-q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 14:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.0.30:1313/posts/podcasts-2019-q1/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>These are my currently podcast reccomendations for Q1 2019</p>
<h2 id="the-butterfly-effect">The Butterfly Effect</h2>
<p>Jon Ronson&rsquo;s Audible exclusive (now available everywhere) where he explores the affect PornHub had on the porn industy. Very insighful and interesting, each episodes covering a broad area such as the impact on kids in school. Only 7 (+1 bonus) episodes but still covers a lot.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Ep. 1: A Nondescript Building in Montreal</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-last-days-of-august">The Last Days of August</h2>
<p>Following on from The Butterfly Effect, released this year on Audible (public release in April), Jon explores the death of a famous porn star and the mystery surrounding her death and her husband.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started-1">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Ep. 1</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="bear-brook">Bear Brook</h2>
<p>True Crime stories focussed around two barrels of bodies found in the woods. The podcast covers how crime investigations methodologies were changed forever by the techniques used.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started-2">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Ep. 1: Hide and Seek</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="this-american-life">This American Life</h2>
<p>A classic podcast but some recent episodes are worth a mention, first covers</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started-3">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>#661: But that&rsquo;s what happened</li>
<li>#657: The Runaways</li>
<li>#486: Valentines Day (Act 2 in particular)</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="cortex">Cortex</h2>
<p>Two youtube/podcast company owners discuss productivity, goal planning, efficiency and technology</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started-4">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>78: State of the Apps 2019</li>
<li>72: Adulting Complete</li>
<li>79: 2019 Yearly Themes</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>]]></description>
      
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast reccomendations - 04/2018</title>
      <link>http://192.168.0.30:1313/posts/podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 22:03:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.0.30:1313/posts/podcasts/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>These are my currently podcast reccomendations as of April 2018</p>
<h2 id="reply-all">Reply All</h2>
<p>Every week, you&rsquo;re presented with an intersting tale relating to the internet. From online bounty hunters to crowdsourcing medical advice, this podcast&rsquo;s range of stories are always interesting and worth a listen.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Long Distance : #102 / #103</li>
<li>The Secret Life of Alex Goldman : #96</li>
<li>Boy in Photo : #79</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="this-american-life">This American Life</h2>
<p>This American Life is one of the most popular podcasts of all time. With over twenty years worth of archives, the amount of amazing episodes are endless.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started-1">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Human Error in Voltile Situations : #634</li>
<li>20 Acts in 60 Minutes : #241</li>
<li>Five Women : #640</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="my-favourite-murder">My Favourite Murder</h2>
<p>Every week, the hosts tell some of their favourite, most interesting true crime, murder stories.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started-2">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>My Firstest Murder : #1</li>
<li>Decompressions : #102</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="sawbones">Sawbones</h2>
<p>A look into the history of how illnesses and medcial problems were <em>solved</em> throughout time. Makes you wonder if we&rsquo;re as wrong now as our ancestors were.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started-3">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>The Women Who Gave Birth to Rabbits</li>
<li>Opioid Addiction</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="no-such-thing-as-a-fish">No Such Thing As A Fish</h2>
<p>The researches behind the facts for QI talk about their favourites facts of the week.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started-4">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Really any, they&rsquo;re all great</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="page-94-the-private-eye-podcast">Page 94: The Private Eye Podcast</h2>
<p>A more detailed look into some stories within Private Eye.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started-5">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Hospital and Hacks</li>
<li>Credit and Christmas</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="disect">Disect</h2>
<p>Long form music analysis, each season focussing on an album.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started-6">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>S2E1 - Kanye West: The Elephant in the Room</li>
<li>S1E9 - Alright by Kendrick Lamar</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="hello-internet">Hello Internet</h2>
<p>Two very inteligent, insightful and interesting people discuss topics of note; always thought provoking.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started-7">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Being Wrong on The Internet, #1</li>
<li>Mr Chompers, #93</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="freakonomics">Freakonomics</h2>
<p>Two economist explore the hidden side of everything, from pizza stores to chuck e cheeses.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started-8">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>What Are you Waiting For?</li>
<li>How Big is My Penis? (And Other Things We Ask Google)</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="my-dad-wrote-a-porno">My Dad Wrote A Porno</h2>
<p>I think the title of this one really says it all.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started-9">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>S1E1 - &lsquo;The Job Interview;&rsquo;</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="mortified">Mortified</h2>
<p>Adults tell the embarrassing stories of things they did as kids.</p>
<h3 id="episodes-to-get-started-10">Episodes to get started</h3>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Titanic Ruined My Love Life, #88</li>
<li>How to Become a Catfish, #105</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="notable-mentions">Notable mentions</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>S-Town, Serial, Crimetown</p>
</blockquote>]]></description>
      
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
